<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Khronos Project</title><link>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Khronos Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How does Khronos work?</title><link>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/how-khronos-works/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/how-khronos-works/</guid><description>How does Khronos work? Khronos is a watchdog - a mechanism that runs in the background, continuously monitoring client clock (which is updated by NTPv4) and calculating an estimated offset. When the offset exceeds a predefined threshold, this is interpreted as the client experiencing a time shifting attack. In this case, Khronos updates the client&amp;rsquo;s clock.
When the client is not under attack, Khronos is passive, allowing NTPv4 to control the client&amp;rsquo;s clock and providing the ordinary high precision and accuracy of NTPv4.</description></item><item><title>Khronos Guarantees</title><link>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/khronos-guarantees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/khronos-guarantees/</guid><description>Khronos Guarantees Time shifting attacks: Analytical results show that if a local Khronos pool consists of 500 servers, 1/7 of whom are controlled by a machine-in-the-middle attacker, and 15 servers are queried in each Khronos poll interval, then success in shifting time of a Khronos client by even a small degree (100 ms), takes many years of effort (over 20 years in expectation).
Dos Attacks: In addition to evaluating the probability of an attacker successfully shifting time at the client&amp;rsquo;s clock, we also evaluated the probability that the attacker succeeds in launching a DoS attack on the servers by causing many clients to enter a panic mode (and query all the servers in their local Khronos pools).</description></item><item><title>Security Analysis Overview</title><link>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/security-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/security-analysis/</guid><description>Security Analysis Overview Time-samples that are at most w away from UTC are considered &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo;, whereas other samples are considered &amp;ldquo;malicious&amp;rdquo;. Two scenarios are considered:
Less than 2/3 of the queried servers are under the attacker&amp;rsquo;s control. The attacker controls more than 2/3 of the queried servers. The first scenario, where there are more than 1/3 good samples, consists of two cases:
(i) there is at least one good sample in the set of samples not eliminated by Khronos (in the middle third of samples) (ii) there are no good samples in the remaining set of samples.</description></item><item><title>What does Khronos protect from?</title><link>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/khronos-protection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://khronos.nwtime.org/about/khronos-protection/</guid><description>What does Khronos protect from? Khronos is designed to protect NTP clients from time shifting attacks.
Who can enforce time shifting attacks?
Time shifting attacks on NTP clients can be based on interfering with the communication between the NTP clients and servers or compromising the servers themselves. Time shifting attacks on NTP are possible even if NTP communication is encrypted and authenticated. A weaker machine-in-the-middle (MitM) attacker can shift time simply by dropping or delaying packets, whereas a powerful attacker, who has full control over an NTP server, can do so by explicitly determining the NTP response content.</description></item></channel></rss>